Dr. Vladimir O. Talibov

Neversvägen 43 SE 22479 Lund, Sweden +460728453329 vladimir.o.talibov@gmail.com http://vtalibov.xyz

Summary

Protein chemist with an interest in early stage drug discovery. Experienced in biosensors, fragment screening, biophysical techniques and structural methods. Keen to set up new expertises and methodologies that are required for a successful project development.

Skills

<u>Experimental</u>: Biophysical methods (SPR, MST, TSA), protein crystallisation, expression&purification, synchrotron-based MX, enzymology.

<u>Computer:</u> *nix, Python (numerical analysis, data processing), T_EX, crystallographic suites, KNIME.

Languages: English, Russian, Swedish (basic).

Expertise: FBLD, early-stage drug design, biophysical methods, protein chemistry.

Experience

Researcher

2019 - current

MAX IV laboratory, Lund, Sweden

- Beamline development and user support as a beamline scientist.
- Design, maintenance and curation of in-house fragment library; development of operational protocols for MAX IV fragment screening facility.

Laboratory Assistant

2012 - 2014

OOO "Biochip-IMB", Moscow, Russia

- Clinical chemistry: development and benchmarking of protein microarray-based diagnostic assays.
- QC of proteins and reactive small molecules.

Education

PhD in Biochemistry

2014 - 2019

Uppsala University, Uppsala, Sweden

Biophysical methods, protein crystallography.

Thesis: "Interaction kinetic analysis in drug design, enzymology and protein research"

BSc&MSc in Chemistry

2008 - 2013

Moscow State University, Moscow, Russia

Interests

Protein chemistry, methods for FBLD, drug design, protein-ligand interfaces.

Publications

- [1] E. Fabini, V. O. Talibov, F. Mihalic, M. Naldi, M. Bartolini, C. Bertucci, A. Del Rio, and U. H. Danielson. "Unveiling the biochemistry of the epigenetic regulator SMYD3". In: *Biochemistry* 58.35 (2019), pp. 3634–3645.
- [2] V. O. Talibov, V. Linkuvienė, U. H. Danielson, and D. Matulis. "Kinetic Analysis of Carbonic Anhydrase–Sulfonamide Inhibitor Interactions". In: *Carbonic Anhydrase as Drug Target*. Springer, Cham, 2019, pp. 125–140.
- [3] V. Linkuviene, V. O. Talibov, U. H. Danielson, and D. Matulis. "Introduction of intrinsic kinetics of protein–ligand interactions and their implications for drug design". In: *J. Med. Chem.* 61.6 (2018), pp. 2292–2302.
- [4] C. Seeger, V. O. Talibov, and U. H. Danielson. "Biophysical analysis of the dynamics of calmodulin interactions with neurogranin and Ca2+/calmodulin-dependent kinase II". In: *J. Mol. Recognit.* 30.8 (2017), e2621.
- [5] V. O. Talibov, V. Linkuvienė, D. Matulis, and U. H. Danielson. "Kinetically selective inhibitors of human carbonic anhydrase isozymes I, II, VII, IX, XII, and XIII". In: J. Med. Chem. 59.5 (2016), pp. 2083–2093.
- [6] V. I. Butvilovskaya, M. V. Tsybulskaya, A. A. Tikhonov, V. O. Talibov, P. V. Belousov, A. Y. Sazykin, A. M. Schwartz, S. A. Surzhikov, A. A. Stomakhin, O. N. Solopova, et al. "Preparation of recombinant serpins B3 and B4 and investigation of their specific interactions with antibodies using hydrogel-based microarrays". In: *Mol. Biol.* 49.5 (2015), pp. 705–713.
- [7] B. Koos, G. Cane, K. Grannas, L. Löf, L. Arngården, J. Heldin, C.-M. Clausson, A. Klaesson, M. K. Hirvonen, F. M. De Oliveira, et al. "Proximity-dependent initiation of hybridization chain reaction". In: *Nat. Commun.* 6 (2015), p. 7294.
- [8] G. U. Feyzkhanova, M. A. Filippova, V. O. Talibov, E. I. Dementieva, V. V. Maslennikov, Y. P. Reznikov, N. Offermann, A. S. Zasedatelev, A. Y. Rubina, and M. Fooke-Achterrath. "Development of hydrogel biochip for in vitro allergy diagnostics". In: *J. Immunol. Methods* 406 (2014), pp. 51–57.
- [9] A. Y. Rubina, G. U. Feizkhanova, M. A. Filippova, V. O. Talibov, M. Fooke-Achterrath, and A. S. Zasedatelev. "Multiplex assay of allergen-specific and total immunoglobulins of E and G classes in the biochip format". In: 447.1 (2012), p. 289.